OLUWAFEMI **S**OSANYA

Owutu road, Agric Ikorodu, Lagos • +234-70-6244-9225 • femi_sosanya@yahoo.com • linkedin.com/in/oluwafemi-sosanya

SUMMARY

Creative Front-End Engineer offering 4+ years of experience providing high-impact web solutions for diverse industry organizations with a proven ability to collaborate effectively with senior & junior developers while spending extra time being mentored and as well mentoring others. I transformed my team at Charisol by seeking, learning, and teaching new, efficient technologies to make aggressive deadlines consistently achievable. Went the extra mile to ensure the customers were unquestionably satisfied with the product or service, which increased customer satisfaction by 25%.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Mkobobank, Yaba, Lagos

May 2022 - Present

Frontend Engineer

- Manage website development projects from initial design through completion, optimizing all cross-browser and multi-platform compatibility for smooth user experience.
- Built cross-browser compatible and accessibility-compliant websites, resulting in 22% faster load time than the industry average.
- Implemented enhancements that improved web functionality and responsiveness for a good user experience.
- Authored the new official Mkobobank website and implemented SEO strategies for user acquisition, driving acquisition up by an average of 250% each month with the Growth manager.
- Worked with design, product, and back-end teams to create the Mkobobank Partners web app to achieve 100% client satisfaction.

Charisol LTD, New York, NY

Oct 2020 – Apr 2022

Lead Frontend Engineer

- Performed code reviews and bug fixes, increasing customer experience by 30% within the first quarter.
- Mentored 4 junior front-end developers on JavaScript and Redux, and trained on the documentation practices used within the organization to achieve high performance and meet goals.
- Highly involved in the entire product development process from ideation to development and improvement for features on Maildrip, reaching over 50,000 users.
- Conduct training for clients on handling website content management systems, decreasing support tickets by 15%.
- Created a compatible, custom client dashboard, reducing support tickets by 45%.
- Assisted in building 100% reusable code and libraries for future use.
- Optimized 4 applications for maximum speed and scalability.
- Produced multiple visual elements of web applications by translating UI/UX design wireframes into code, producing high-quality markup using HTML5 and CSS3.
- Worked closely with an agile team of 9 members and provided end-to-end solutions for clients.

Freelance, Ikorodu, Lagos

Mar 2018 – Apr 2022

Software Developer

- Relocated a multipage user experience into a single-page application, improving customer engagement by 12%.
- Engineered websites from front to backend using the MERN stack
- Enhanced user experience and accomplished webpage objectives by creating site structure, navigation, page optimization, and graphics integration.
- Work closely with programmers and clients to meet project requirements, goals, and desired functionality.

 Constructed and maintained both corporate and client websites, using scripting languages and content management systems, including WordPress.

Digital Flames Tech, Ibadan, Oyo

May 2008 – Dec 2014

Frontend Developer

- Using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and WordPress, I created several high-powered and browser-compatible pages.
- Collaborated with UX/UI design teams to improve checkout flow; increased conversion rates by 20%.
- Enable site-wide promotions by programming HTML5 canvases to animate particles on web backgrounds.
- Validated 100% of user input before submitting to the back-end.

EDUCATION

Tai Solarin University of Education, Ijagun, Ogun

Nov 2015

• B.Sc.(Ed) in Economics

SKILLS

Languages:

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Typescript
- PHP

Libraries:

- React
- jQuery
- Redux, Redux-Toolkit

Frameworks:

- Nextjs
- Express.js
- Vue.js
- Angular

Testing:

- Jest
- Cypress

CI/CD:

• Git

Database:

- MongoDB
- MySQL
- Firebase

Others:

- REST, GraphQL, RTK-Query, Axios, React-Query
- Node JS, EJS. HBS
- GitHub, GitLab, Docker
- Notion, Slack, Jira
- Adobe XD, Figma, Premier Pro, Adobe Audition
- SCSS, LESS, Bootstrap, Styled Components, Material UI, Tailwind CSS, Chakra UI, Ant Design, WordPress

PUBLICATIONS

The Effect of Exchange Rate Devaluation on Economic Growth in Nigeria

2015

Final year research project, Economics Department of Tai Solarin University of Education.

LANGUAGES

- English
- Yoruba

CONTACT & SOCIALS

GitHub: https://github.com/boomshakar **LinkedIn**: linkedin.com/in/oluwafemi-sosanya

Skype: https://join.skype.com/invite/DrdxeIBRhW1i

Mobile: +(234)70-6244-9225 Email: femi_sosanya@yahoo.com